PRO BONO
PREVIOUSLY
The defendant is sentenced to ten years
in prison and a fine of 70 billion won.
Chief Judge Kang Da-wit
levied a harsher sentence
than anyone anticipated
on JS Group CEO Jang Hyeon-bae
and has instantly become
the people's judge.
Your classmate
from elementary school called.
-"Kim Ju-seop"?
-My goodness!
The people's judge!
Good luck!
An apple box filled with 1.2 billion won
in the car of an anti-corruption judge.
I trusted and guided you
when you were a nobody
without a college degree.
How could you betray me like this,
you snake?
That bastard…
is Yoo Jae-beom, who I tried
for being a serial con artist.
He's wanted right now!
Submit your resignation letter
right away.
Come join my law firm.
I've already persuaded Dad.
You persuaded Dr. Oh?
I want you to help me.
-I'll take charge…
-Welcome to the team!
…of those pro bono losers for a year.
You want to make a deal?
You haven't asked me once
about what made me quit as a judge.
Have you seen the video, by any chance?
It's been a while, Mr. Yoo Jae-beom.
Yes, it has been a while, Ms. Oh.
Don't let Da-wit fool you.
He's a criminal who took a huge bribe.
And he's a brutal murderer who pushed
-a good businessman to death.
-Ms. Park?
No matter how I look at it, it was you.
And there's no trace of manipulation.
That's your number, right?
What are you talking about?
I've never called…
Good morning!
Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
Remember how you asked me
to keep tabs on Ms. Yoon
-and find out who she meets?
-Right.
The chief of Seoul Central District Court,
your former workplace.
-What?
-…recommended Shin Jung-seok,
Chief of Seoul Central District Court,
to the president as a new justice.
It's a recording transcript
made by Ms. Seo, who you fired.
It's what you discussed on the phone
regarding the appeal case
of CEO Jang Hyeon-bae
with someone in the Supreme Court.
That's how I looked
-under anesthesia?
-Yes.
It's retrograde amnesia.
Instead of being drunk from alcohol,
I was drunk from sleep?
They said you'd take my case.
The presiding judge abused his power
and killed my father
through a manipulated trial.
What was the name of the presiding judge?
Kang Da-wit.
PRO BONO
EPISODE 9
-Let's step outside and talk.
-Sure.
You sure made
a lot of noise during that trial.
I'll take it as a compliment, sir.
Since they took it
to the National Assembly and won,
please reconsider disbanding the team.
"Disbanding"?
He won over a client and admirably
fulfilled the terms of the bet.
But what are you talking about?
You said our client wasn't Elijah,
but EK Entertainment…
The CEO of EK Entertainment
was arrested.
And their assets have been frozen,
so it's an empty shell.
You don't want a penniless client, do you?
That girl, Elijah.
She'll establish
her own agency now, won't she?
Of course, Oh & Partners
will sign them to a contract
to provide full legal consultation.
Right, Attorney Kang?
Good job.
I was nervous about coming
to Oh & Partners,
but that office
is nice and unique, Ms. Park.
-It was you, wasn't it?
-About what?
DON'T LET DA-WIT FOOL YOU
You let me down, Ms. Park.
Aren't you a pro bono attorney
who helps the powerless?
Why have you been sitting on
this tip for public interest?
I guess legal professionals
are all the same.
But I'm not surprised.
People look out for their own kind.
It's so upsetting for those without power.
I have nothing to say to a con artist.
You used an anesthetic substance,
didn't you?
Goodness, I'm honored.
To receive a compliment
from a giant in the legal world as you,
that's no ordinary feat.
But I've pulled that feat off.
You mean a monster, not a giant.
Who would say such a thing?
No, the legal world
has always admired you as a role model--
It's okay.
I prefer being a monster.
It's means people are afraid of me.
However,
I've overindulged my only daughter so much
that she's turned into a spoiled brat.
I'm very worried.
Nonsense. I'm a good daughter
who always listens to you
and cares only about you.
It must have been some kind of benzo.
Using his short-term memory loss,
you made him hold an apple box
while he was disoriented
and framed him
as if he were taking a box of cash.
Yes, that's right.
I'm impressed, Ms. Park.
-Are you admitting it?
-Yes, I am.
It was just as you said,
but with a little more detail.
Now, you need to ask me about my motive.
-Your motive?
-Yes.
Why did I have to do such a thing
to Kang Da-wit,
a justice candidate
and "the people's judge"?
Why did I voluntarily come to you
when I'm on the run for fraud?
Shouldn't you ask me those things?
"When Mr. Kang was a judge,
he killed my father
through a manipulated trial."
Why on earth would he do that?
You should ask that yourself to that scum…
To Kang Da-wit.
I assume you've been through a lot,
but you expect me to trust those words?
From someone who's framing
my colleague with a fake video?
No, don't trust my words.
Trust the evidence.
Everything is in here.
I've spent the past ten years
gathering these.
I'll take a look,
but don't expect me to believe you.
And you'll have to take responsibility
for using a fake video
to falsely accuse Mr. Kang.
You're going to report me?
-Yes, I have to.
-No, you won't be able to.
Why can't I…
You just said you'd review my case.
"Attorneys must not divulge
confidential information
learned from the client."
You're obligated
to maintain confidentiality. Oh, no.
Even in the consultation stage.
Okay.
Please read through them carefully.
And come visit me.
Visit you?
Yes.
I'm a serial con artist
on the run, aren't I?
I'm going to turn myself in
to the police.
Ms. Park, look.
I've put everything on the line.
The thing about me is…
I don't care if I go to hell…
as long as I can expose
Kang Da-wit's hypocrisy.
I'm surprised. I thought he'd be furious.
Father did something.
-What?
-There's something going on.
Be careful. Both you and Team Pro Bono.
About what?
Hey, why…
Being nosy isn't my thing.
Find out who Dr. Oh has been meeting
inside and outside the firm.
Wait.
Get me the firm's visitor log too.
Ms. Park.
-Yes?
-Is there something going on?
It seemed like you were familiar
with that guy from before.
It's nothing.
It's…
An external organization
introduced him to us.
I'll review the case first
and let you know.
Okay, I got it.
If you need to talk about it,
let me know anytime.
Okay. Thank you, Mr. Jang.
No problem.
Mr. Kang!
What's with that expression?
Are we really being disbanded?
-What?
-Didn't you just meet with Dr. Oh?
I did.
I heard he was furious
because we sued our client.
Are we really going to be
thrown out into the street?
Why are you making such a fuss?
We did our job as attorneys. That's all.
Hey, you were so worried all morning,
you read the same file a hundred times!
-Why pretend to be cool?
-What? When did I ever?
Nan-hui, you scared?
What?
He complimented us
for bringing in a star client like Elijah.
Oh, my gosh!
Didn't you just say I was making a fuss?
Get back to work. It's no big deal.
Geez, look at Nan-hui changing her tune.
Ms. Park, what's with the long face?
Didn't you hear me?
Our team won't be disbanded.
Right.
I'm so happy.
You did a great job.
You did a wonderful job, Mr. Kang.
Dr. Oh doesn't usually
take back what he says.
Good job, everyone.
Is there something going on?
No, nothing's going on.
All right, since we're feeling good,
let's have an early lunch.
Ox knee soup and boiled beef?
Sounds good.
Ms. Park, you like ox knee soup.
Yes, sounds good.
Well, well!
This is totally ox-hilarating!
-Wasn't that awful?
-I thought it was funny.
-What was funny about it?
-It wasn't funny?
JOIE DE VIVRE
BURNT CUP NOODLE SHOWS
WORKING CONDITIONS
CEO YOO CHARGED OVER PAPER MILL FIRE
WRITTEN STATEMENT
SEOUL SOUTHERN DISTRICT COURT
TRIAL RECORDS
JUDGE KANG DA-WIT
YEONG-SIL, NAN-HUI, JUN-U
INVITE TO GROUP CHAT
Let's have an emergency meeting.
DEBT COLLECTION ASSIGNMENT
What's that?
Nothing.
You're going to work early today.
I'll get going.
CREDITOR JC CAPITAL
DEBTOR PARK CHANG-SUN
I mean, 7:30 a.m.? Come on.
What's going on?
Why did you call a meeting this early?
Gi-ppeum, pro bono attorneys
are laborers too.
Sleeping in is our basic right.
Is this about Mr. Kang?
What? What do you mean?
He's the only one who's absent.
And yesterday, you met with someone
who was sent by The Alliance
of Judicial Victims, right?
A judicial victim?
Is it someone who was tried
by Mr. Kang when he was a judge?
Yes.
Geez, that's all?
Then what? Are you saying
Mr. Kang manipulated a trial or something?
Yeah.
That's exactly it.
-What?
Wait, I've seen some of the cases
that alliance has sent before.
Most of them were baseless claims.
Yeah, when they think they lost unfairly,
they question the judge first.
Yeah.
But…
He brought evidence.
That's why I called this meeting.
INVESTIGATION REPORT ON FIRE
DEFENDANT YOO BAEK-MAN
Yoo Baek-man is the father of the person
who came to me, Yoo Jae-beom.
He was a businessman
who ran a paper mill
called Woongcheon Paper in Woongcheon.
We've now moved
to Jangwol Industrial Complex.
As his business expanded,
he moved it to Jangwol Industrial Complex
in the capital city.
But ten years ago,
a tragic fire broke out in the factory.
Fire!
The factory burned down,
and a person died as well.
Oh, my gosh.
They found out that the old
electrical system had short circuited.
They didn't have
enough fire escape routes either.
The factory manager,
who was in charge of on-site safety,
was arrested and charged.
The judge presiding over the case was…
It was Mr. Kang.
Yes.
Wait.
About Yoo Jae-beom,
you said his father was the CEO,
not the factory manager.
That's right.
Then why…
The defendant…
was changed by Mr. Kang.
FACTORY MANAGER, CEO YOO BAEK-MAN
What?
10 YEARS AGO
SEOUL SOUTHERN DISTRICT COURT
By authority,
the Court grants bail to the defendant.
Your Honor, the trial has just begun.
What do you mean?
The CEO, not the factory manager.
Go get Yoo Baek-man.
Otherwise, I cannot proceed…
with this trial.
A judge granted bail
to the factory manager
with his authority at the first hearing?
That's rare, isn't it?
That's pretty much
an open display of his presumptions.
And he took control
of the prosecutor's investigation
to change the defendant to the CEO.
Gosh, even when Mr. Kang was a judge,
-he wasn't any ordinary person.
-Jun-u.
This isn't something to be amazed about.
A judge can't cross the line.
Exactly. And after that,
he started doing the things
he's known for.
What? If they're things
he's known for, then…
He called them.
The journalists.
10 YEARS AGO
AFTER WOONGCHEON PAPER FIRE
The editorial desk has been hounding us
to find a juicy story.
They chewed us out last time
for being a step behind
on reporting the LNG explosion. Geez.
Don't even get me started.
Here.
-What is this?
-This looks like cup noodles.
You know about the fire
at the Woongcheon Paper factory, right?
Sorry?
The one where someone died?
This is from that site?
The one who died was a trainee
from a technical high school.
He was 17 years old.
Goodness.
That came out of his backpack.
I guess he was going to eat that
and work late.
My goodness.
So?
Come on. Tell us in detail, Judge Kang.
No, let's not make a toast.
Come closer.
Hey, I know that cup noodle picture.
It was on the news for a while.
Mr. Kang leaked it, didn't he?
That is exactly something
Mr. Kang would do.
Then, things started to happen
as if by magic.
IT WASN'T AN INDUSTRIAL ACCIDENT
This led to protests and media coverage.
The protesters argue
this tragedy wasn't an accident.
After initially refusing to act,
the prosecution charged the owner Yoo.
Those involved, including
the factory manager, changed their stories
and started testifying
against Yoo Baek-man.
In the end…
10 YEARS AGO
SEOUL SOUTHERN DISTRICT COURT
Mr. Yoo.
Yes, Your Honor?
There's something
I've been meaning to ask.
Sorry?
Yes, go ahead.
Has it ever crossed your mind
that the workers at your factory
have loving families too?
Pardon?
Well, of course.
They're not machines that make you money.
They are people of flesh and blood.
Do you know that?
Excuse me, Your Honor.
I…
My company…
The Court rules
the defendant is sentenced
to seven years in prison.
Your Honor!
-The defendant will be taken into custody.
-Your Honor!
-Please take him away.
-No!
Your Honor!
Your Honor, let me explain…
Your Honor! This isn't fair, Your Honor!
-That's enough!
-Your Honor!
-Wait, hold on!
Wasn't that before the Serious Accidents
Punishment Act was enacted?
Seven years in prison would be
the maximum under the Occupational
Safety and Health Act.
For the individual business owner?
How was it upheld by higher courts?
If it was ten years ago, it'd be
right after the sinking of MV Sewol.
That's right.
Backlash after public tragedies
must've been intense then.
A flood of articles praised Mr. Kang
as a brave, young judge.
He started gaining popularity then.
This sounds exactly
like something Mr. Kang would do.
Is that wrong?
-What?
-Honestly,
I didn't like him at first.
That was obvious.
But after working with him for a while,
I wonder if it's bad
to have someone like him around.
The law is on the side
of the powerful anyway.
If we can win once in a while like this…
If we can give people hope
that they can win,
how great would it be
for those who always lose?
-Ms. Yoo…
-This case isn't any different.
Mr. Kang can be attention-seeking
and materialistic,
but he wouldn't make something up
out of thin air.
That CEO must've done something bad
that he was responsible for.
But playing by the book didn't work.
So, Mr. Kang used all possible means
to hold him accountable!
Am I wrong? Don't you all think so?
Nan-hui.
Yoo Baek-man died in jail…
-from pent-up anger.
-What?
What?
This is the statement Yoo Jae-beom got
from the factory manager.
It says Judge Kang
blatantly placed the blame
on Mr. Yoo Baek-man during the trial,
and he said he could only play along.
Mr. Kang really went that far?
It's a manipulated…
It was a manipulated trial.
If that's true,
Mr. Kang is a criminal.
Yes.
Wait…
Still, we can't take this case.
Am I wrong?
He's our team leader.
He's our colleague!
Also, if our team leader
gets in trouble for this,
that'll be the final nail
in the coffin for our team.
We barely survived
by winning the last case.
We worked so hard to win that.
Yeong-sil.
Good morning!
Gosh, everyone's here early today.
Come on.
Why do you feel so down?
What's going on? Say something
The mood is so cold
Hey, Mr. Jang!
Get rid of that broken one,
and let's use this one now.
The team Dr. Oh complimented
deserves something like this.
Right, Ms. Yoo? You love coffee.
The mood is so cold
I need to go to the archives.
Let's go together.
-The archives are here. Where are you…
-Mr. Kang.
-Yes?
-Can I have a word with you?
About what?
That lowlife Yoo Jae-beom came here?
-Yes.
-Why didn't you tell me?
Where is that jerk?
-Mr. Kang.
-Why on earth didn't you call me?
We don't have time for this.
Geez!
Detective Woo, it's me.
That punk Yoo Jae-beom is…
He turned himself in.
I'll call you back.
He turned himself in?
-Yes, he's in jail right now.
-Then,
did he admit to framing me?
I'm sorry, but I can't tell you that.
Why not? Why can't you tell me?
He came looking for me.
I heard his story as an attorney.
Wait, don't tell me
you've decided to represent that jerk--
Are you out of your mind, Ms. Park?
-No, I haven't made up my mind yet.
-Then why?
I have to keep confidentiality
even in the consultation stage.
You know this.
That punk, Yoo Jae-beom.
First, he sent you the apple box video.
Now, he came and asked you to defend him?
With a case that's framing me?
What a damn despicable…
That's not it.
Then, is it the fraud case
he'd been running from?
-Mr. Kang.
-What is it then?
Do you know Mr. Yoo Baek-man?
Who is that? I don't know him.
He's Jae-beom's father.
Ma'am, this is the visitor log
from the past week.
Good work.
OH & PARTNERS VISITOR LOG
Wait, this person was here?
Who is that, ma'am?
Who did he meet with?
ATTORNEY PARK GI-PPEUM
Attorney Park Gi-ppeum
from Team Pro Bono.
Yoo Jae-beom is that man's son?
Wait, how…
Then…
Do you remember now
who Mr. Yoo Baek-man is?
Yes.
I remember him now.
It's someone I tried in the past.
I had no idea Yoo Jae-beom was his son.
Yoo Jae-beom believes
that you rigged the trial.
That's ridiculous!
Do you think I'd do such a thing?
A rigged trial? What do you take me for?
-You didn't, right?
-Of course…
Of course, I didn't.
I only followed the law.
So then,
did he say he set a trap for me
because of his grudge?
I'm sorry, but I can't tell you.
Yoo Jae-beom came to me
with evidence he had gathered
to prove you rigged the trial.
He asked Team Pro Bono
to sue you on his behalf.
What evidence did he bring?
I can't tell you. Sorry.
Geez! For crying out loud!
So, are you going to
file a suit against me?
I wanted to hear
what you had to say first.
I have nothing to be ashamed of.
I only did what I had to do.
Okay. So, tell me everything.
-What happened during the trial?
-Yes, I'll tell you.
But…
there's someone I need to see first.
These mint candies.
After establishing this firm,
I'd eat these every time
I stayed up all night.
Back then, we only had three attorneys.
You've told me this story, Father.
When they discontinued the candies,
you bought the factory
so they'd make them again.
I told you that?
Geez, am I getting dementia already?
Hold on.
What time was it today?
Why did you do that?
Do what?
You know what I mean.
Yoo Jae-beom.
I don't know. I have no idea
why you're asking me about that.
You've played a very risky card.
This will endanger the firm as a whole.
Well…
I don't know if someone
who threatened her own father
with a phone transcript can say that.
It's a recording transcript
made by Ms. Seo, who you fired.
It's what you discussed on the phone
regarding the appeal case
of CEO Jang Hyeon-bae.
With someone in the Supreme Court.
Even though I'm an old man
who keeps forgetting stuff,
you acted too rashly, Jung-in.
You should've waited a little more.
You should've remained
a daughter who listens to her dad.
Your father still has
gas left in the tank.
Why don't you step back
from this headache-causing work
and find a hobby to enjoy?
I'll pass.
I'm still busy
protecting this firm you founded
from you.
No,
you'll end up getting some rest.
Isn't today a perfectly beautiful day too?
It'll be a gift.
-What does that mean?
-Right.
It's at 2:00 p.m. today.
This just in.
JS Group CEO Jang Hyeon-bae
had been held in custody
after being sentenced to ten years
in prison by former judge Kang Da-wit.
But the Supreme Court has just reversed
this decision and found him innocent.
Jang has been accusing former judge Kang
of driving the trial on trumped-up charges
to a fixed conclusion.
With today's Supreme Court ruling,
Jang's claims have been given more weight.
-The case has been returned…
-Oh, my God.
…to the High Court for a new trial.
-All eyes will be on…
-Yeong-sil, what's wrong?
-Are you okay?
-Yeah, I'm fine.
The Supreme Court's decision…
But what is this? What is happening?
-Chairman Jang's case was also rigged?
-No, that's not possible.
Gi-ppeum, where's Mr. Kang right now?
What?
He said he had to go meet someone.
Who on earth is he meeting
in the middle of this chaos?
The people's judge, Kang Da-wit!
Da-wit, it's been a while.
It's me, Juvenile.
You're laughing?
Thanks for putting yourself in there.
Who is it? Who did you cook this up with?
"Who"? Is that what you want to know?
You didn't ask me about "why."
Well, you clearly know why now.
Then, did you hear
about how my father passed?
You thought you'd be all right
after pulling this stunt
on a sitting chief judge?
No.
You're not a sitting judge anymore.
You…
You'll pay dearly
for all these tricks you've pulled.
Really?
How?
Catching you was the difficult part.
Revealing what you've done
won't be a problem.
Is that so?
In the end, it was nothing special.
You tampered with my drink
when I went to the restroom. Am I wrong?
I want to send my friend off first.
-All right. I'll get going.
-Okay.
Please drive safely.
-That driver was your accomplice.
-Okay.
When I fell asleep from the drugs,
you woke me up to move the apple box.
"I brought some apples
from my orchard. Take some."
Hey.
-It's so heavy. Gosh.
-Hey.
And when I got in the car again
and fell asleep,
you replaced that box with a box of cash
since they differ in weight.
That's interesting.
You've done a lot of research.
I didn't need to research.
You damn frauds aren't that creative.
You've written a nice story.
But you know, don't you? In the end…
You won't be able to prove anything.
Genes are pretty scary.
I guess it must…
run in your family.
Shamelessness.
Pretending to be the victim.
Things like that.
You dug into my past,
so you know about my mother's case.
Do you know what shocked me the most
during your father's trial?
He didn't remember me at all.
He couldn't care less about the son
of a worker whose hand was cut off.
That's the kind of people you are.
You cause others…
so much pain…
and you ignore them.
Do you know what shocked me the most?
You mercilessly dragged my father
to jail right in front of me…
but you couldn't remember me at all.
-The defendant will be taken into custody.
-Your Honor!
Please take him away.
-All rise.
Father.
Hold on. Father!
Your Honor!
Father! Wait!
You think you're any better?
Do you?
RISK MANAGEMENT
JS GROUP CEO JANG HYEON-BAE ACQUITTED
How will you take responsibility?
With Chairman Jang's acquittal,
the business world's been in an uproar.
Putting one of the five biggest CEOs
of the business world
into court custody without evidence?
Is Kang Da-wit out of his mind?
I will take care of it, no matter what.
How? How are you going to do that?
You are the one who hired such a person.
What client would entrust us
with their cases now?
Even though the Supreme Court
has acquitted him,
there's still the retrial--
Step down.
All right?
Attorney Oh.
Mr. Kim.
Are you going to shut down
the firm your father built?
It's the will
of the entire management group.
Please step down from your position
as CEO, Attorney Oh Jung-in.
JOURNALIST KIM DO-HUN
Hey, Mr. Kim. What is it?
You know the Supreme Court reversed
Jang Hyeon-bae's case, right?
-What are you talking about?
-Jang's attorneys…
They're talking to the press right now.
Former judge Kang Da-wit presided
the first trial with a predetermined…
They're all attacking you.
Would you like to comment on this?
Who was the presiding justice
that made the ruling?
Justice Shin Jung-seok.
He was chief of the court
you used to work at.
-Give us a few words.
-Hang up for a second.
I knew it.
Dr. Oh!
Hello, sir!
You can sit. Don't let me interrupt.
Hello, sir. I'm Park Gi-ppeum.
I'm Yoo Nan-hui.
Right. I'm Jang… Jang Yeong-sil.
Hello, Dr. Oh!
I'm Hwang Jun-u, a young attorney
who always does his best!
What brings you here
to our humble office?
Humble?
These are the files of trials
that I would study all night
when I was about your age.
This is a place that feels like home.
-Please take a seat, sir.
-Right.
-No, it's okay.
-Yes, sir.
Team Pro Bono.
You've done so well so far.
I didn't pay enough attention to you.
I should have called you up
and given you some encouragement.
It's okay, sir.
We're just grateful that you allowed
our team to stay in this firm.
It seems there's a hidden meaning
in what you just said.
No, sir. She…
What Ms. Park meant was…
Attorney Park.
I heard you got a client
asking you to sue Attorney Kang.
Yes, sir.
-Why don't you take it?
-Pardon?
Sir, how could we…
Aren't you pro bono attorneys?
Isn't it your job to help the victims
of abuse-of-power crimes?
Or was I mistaken?
Dr. Oh,
what you said was correct,
but he's our team leader.
Rather than take the case ourselves,
we should find other pro bono attorneys…
If there's anyone
who doesn't want to follow my orders,
tell me now.
No one?
Then, good luck.
Dr. Oh.
We're pro bono attorneys.
To see if it's of public interest,
we should at least hear Mr. Kang's story
before making a decision.
Hearing both sides is a basic requirement
for any attorney, isn't it?
Did you learn that from Da-wit?
Talking about basic requirements
in front of me?
Sir?
Okay.
Good luck with the basics.
Do it like pro bono attorneys.
Have a good day, sir!
Why did you do that?
SUPREME COURT
JUSTICE SHIN JUNG-SEOK
Come in.
Judge Kang, it's been a while.
Take a seat over there.
It's been a long time, Justice Shin.
Come.
Sit.
This is pu'er tea.
You have more gray hairs now.
Don't even mention it.
You're happy
for only two days as a justice.
The day you're appointed
and the day you retire.
I have so much to do
that I'm drowning in work.
I thought you'd refuse to see me,
so I've come empty-handed.
What? Why would I refuse to see you?
By any chance, is this about
Chairman Jang Hyeon-bae's case?
Come on. You just make rulings
based on your own convictions.
Right.
Judge Kang, did you come to see me
because you were upset about that?
Of course not.
Actually, I feel so terrible
whenever I think about you.
But you seem to be doing
even better out there.
You took a lot of fun cases too.
You think so?
I just met with Yoo Jae-beom.
-What?
-Why did you do that?
What do you mean?
After meeting that punk,
I know for certain now.
The person he trusted
that let him make such a video.
What are you talking about?
Mr. Shin.
I really liked you.
You believed in me
when I had no connections or supporters.
You entrusted me
with the Division for Corruption Cases.
If it wasn't for you, I…
I wouldn't have been fooled
by such a sloppy video.
Someone I'd always trusted and followed.
The first person I'd report to
after discovering a box of cash.
Is that true?
Yes, sir.
Nobody gave all that money,
but it was in a judge's car?
Who's going to buy that?
Are you going to quietly quit
before word gets out?
Or will you face a police investigation
for taking a big bribe
from a serial con artist?
Someone who I'd have
no choice but to follow
because they'd cover things up
if I quietly resigned.
Since that person was the accomplice,
all of it was possible.
What kind of nonsense
are you talking about?
Making Yoo Jae-beom turn himself in
was a fatal mistake.
A Supreme Court justice
who is a serial con artist's accomplice.
Once Yoo Jae-beom starts talking,
Korea's going to be in an uproar.
I understand you're upset
because I couldn't protect you.
But my goodness.
You have a deep emotional wound.
You should see a therapist.
How sad.
You used to be so brilliant.
My goodness.
Judge Kang.
I just met Shin Jung-seok
and brought it up,
but he didn't know
Yoo Jae-beom had turned himself in.
Is that true?
He pretended to be cool,
but he was flustered.
I'm certain of it.
Then, did Yoo Jae-beom
turn himself in on his own?
We don't know that. Or…
there could be someone else.
Anyway, I scared him stiff,
so he'll definitely make a move.
I see.
You want me to tail him, right?
But are you going to give me
hazard pay now, Judge Kang?
-This is--
-Good luck.
Hey, Jung-in.
Now?
You stepped down as CEO? Why?
It's because of me, isn't it?
No.
It was my decision to bring you here.
I'll find a way to take care of this.
-First--
-Let's think about that tomorrow.
Today, let's just drink.
Here.
-Da-wit.
-Yeah?
You were really hurt
back in the JRTI, weren't you?
What? When you dumped me?
Why are you talking about the past?
That's not like you.
I'm sorry.
My father
was actually once a girl dad.
And I was a daughter
who wouldn't dare to disobey him.
If I were him, I would've split us up too.
The princess of Oh & Partners
and a nobody without a college degree.
I totally understand.
But do you remember?
The promise we made
while drinking the day we broke up.
You've forgotten.
I told you back then
that if we were still single
by the time I was 40,
we'd get back together and get married.
I turned 40 today.
What a birthday, isn't it?
Drinks are on me today
since it's my birthday.
CUP NOODLE ISN'T ANYWHERE ON LIST
FABRICATED EVIDENCE
JUDGE KANG EXPOSES
GAPS IN INDUSTRIAL SAFETY
JOIE DE VIVRE
Could you take a look at this?
"Notice of debt collection"?
What is this?
"JC Capital."
Mom, we were made exempt
from liability back then.
I don't know.
They said we were missing
from the creditor's list,
so we're not exempt.
That can't be right.
I'll check it after work.
Don't worry about it, okay?
Okay. Get going.
ATTORNEY KANG DA-WIT
Why did you call me on my way to work?
You weren't even at the office.
It'll only be uncomfortable.
They've all started avoiding me.
Because it's hard on them.
Because they all like you.
If you all like me,
then why are you letting
a con artist fool you?
A manipulated trial?
Why would I do that?
What benefit would I get from it?
That case made you famous.
You did a lot of interviews too.
You think I rigged the trial
to become popular?
You still see me as a scumbag
who's obsessed with success,
while you all are
admirable pro bono attorneys.
What is this?
DON'T LET DA-WIT FOOL YOU
It's the text Yoo Jae-beom sent me
with the video.
-You never told me about this text.
-Because I trusted you!
What?
While handling Byeol and Gang-hun's cases,
I started seeing you differently.
You pretended to be indifferent,
but you were always sincere.
"Someone like him wouldn't do that."
I believed you from the start.
So I ignored this ridiculous text.
And that apple box!
Do you know how many times
I watched that video?
"It clearly must've been altered!"
To find evidence of that, I…
Ms. Park.
Are you really going to take my case?
-They all want to?
-Of course, they don't want to take it!
But we have no choice.
Also, Dr. Oh ordered us directly
to take the case.
-Dr. Oh?
-So,
please tell us everything.
We've all decided
to hear your story first.
Okay?
Where is he going in such a hurry?
Hey, Jun-u.
Wait, that's…
Why is he going in there?
Hey, Gi-ppeum.
Okay, I'll tell everyone to come.
OH GYU-JANG
SENIOR ADVISOR
This is quite disappointing.
We're having a meeting
about a case involving me.
We don't want to believe
that you manipulated a trial.
Then, all you have to do
is not believe it.
You all believe what that fraud says?
There are some things
we have investigated.
What do you mean?
It happened ten years ago.
What could you have investigated?
This is…
Yes, it's the photo
that shifted public opinion on the case.
You gave this to the journalists.
What about it?
We reviewed all trial records from then,
and this photo…
is nowhere to be found.
The student who passed away…
There's no statement that says
he brought the cup noodles.
What on earth is this…
What is this photo, Mr. Kang?
How does this relate
to the main issue of the case?
We don't want
to think this way either, Mr. Kang.
However,
this was the first case
that got you national attention.
Then, you were put on the fast track,
taking key positions.
Mr. Kang, please tell us now.
I guess it can't be helped.
You all see me as a lunatic
obsessed with success.
Mr. Kang…
You'll all end up finding out
from Yoo Jae-beom anyway,
so I'll tell it myself.
Yoo Baek-man…
We've had…
a long, bitter history.
What?
1998, WOONGCHEON PAPER MILL,
WOONGCHEON CITY
Mom, I'm home.
Mom?
Mom.
Mom!
Da-wit, you're home.
I'm sorry I couldn't come to the door.
That's not what's important here.
You have a fever. Why didn't you tell…
It's all right.
It's okay.
I'm all right. It's nothing.
Mom, what happened to your hand?
Mom, your hand.
Mom.
Your hand.
Mom. Tell me!
Mom!
Get a hold of yourselves, okay?
-Don't get soft.
-Let go!
Who are you?
-What the hell? Who is this punk?
-Come here!
You said there were
sudden additional orders
and made my mom work overtime for days.
For some damn pennies?
Damn it!
Get him out now!
Where did that punk come from?
-Let go of me!
-Are you all right, sir?
Get rid of him!
Get out of here, kid.
All right? Hey!
-Let go!
-Leave already! Stop!
-Hey, kid!
-Move.
Sir, please don't.
You rude little brat.
How dare you act like a thug?
Hey, stop making a scene like an idiot.
And go do it the legal way.
I can tell he was raised
without a father. That damn…
HOW TO FILE CRIMINAL COMPLAINTS
HOW TO SUE ON MY OWN
With our situation,
we can't afford to sue.
We don't have money for an attorney.
I'll do it.
I'll handle everything,
so just focus on getting better.
You don't know how the world works yet.
There's no one who will help
a family like us, Da-wit.
So,
-go to college and--
-I said I'd do it, Mom.
Okay.
Goodness. Hello, Chief.
Come on. I retired long ago.
No need to call me "Chief."
My apologies for being late, Your Honor.
It's all right.
Please go ahead.
Actually, I am very sorry about this,
but since the plaintiff has requested
so many documents,
we'd be very grateful if you could
grant us enough time to prepare.
Your Honor, this is already
their third time motioning to postpone!
Order. Lower your voice.
-This is a court of law.
-Da-wit.
Sit down.
Today, we will move
to change the hearing date.
The next hearing date
will be decided upon later.
All rise.
Your Honor!
Da-wit.
Hey, Da-wit.
The ones with money and power
knew how to protect themselves very well.
They dragged out the trial
for a year and a half.
I gave up on college
and tried to keep it going,
but in the end…
The evidence the plaintiff has submitted
is not enough
to prove the defendant's negligence.
The Court finds no basis
for the claim for damages.
Therefore, this case is dismissed.
-All rise.
-Your Honor.
Your Honor, the evidence is right here!
-Your Honor!
-Da-wit.
Mom.
Mom!
Mom, are you all right? Mom!
Just promise me…
two things.
Cremate me
and spread my ash over a river…
so that you won't have to
come to see me every year.
Okay?
Mom.
Don't look back.
Keep moving forward.
Just keep moving forward…
without stopping.
Da-wit, you must…
become successful.
You have to succeed
so people won't look down on you.
Go as far…
as you can, my son.
Got it?
Mom.
Mom…
Mom, no.
Mom!
No, Mom.
And that was how my mother passed away.
Only then
did Yoo give a small sum for compensation.
Mom.
Even though…
I couldn't keep my promise
to spread your ashes over a river,
I'll keep my promise to make it
as high as I can.
I'll ease your sorrow, Mom.
Mr. Kang…
That's why I chose a career in law.
I'm just like all of you.
I wanted to become a judge
who applied the law fairly to everyone
so that no one would feel
as if they were treated unjustly
like my mother was.
You see,
I'd never do anything
to embarrass my mother.
I have many faults as a human being.
But as a judge,
I've never crossed the line.
I'm sorry.
I didn't know what you went through.
I've been so mean to you.
I just thought you were
some despicable guy
who'd always been privileged
and on the fast track.
I understand.
I do look especially elegant.
I was right about the despicable part.
Mr. Kang.
I had no idea either.
It must have been so tough
-at such a young age.
-It's all right.
I'm not the only one
who's been through tough times.
What are you thinking so hard about?
At the very least,
you didn't recuse yourself.
What?
If you had trouble in the past
with the defendant Yoo Baek-man,
shouldn't you have recused yourself?
For a fair trial?
-Jun-u…
-What?
Am I wrong?
Jun-u's right.
Ms. Park…
Do you remember, Mr. Kang?
When I first brought up
Yoo Baek-man's name…
Do you know Mr. Yoo Baek-man?
Who is that? I don't know him.
You said you didn't know him.
-It's a name you wouldn't forget.
-Well, that's…
I was briefly mistaken
to suddenly hear…
When I suddenly mentioned
trial manipulation, how did you respond?
Yoo Jae-beom believes
that you rigged the trial.
That's ridiculous!
Do you think I'd do such a thing?
A rigged trial? What do you take me for?
You taught us about the instinctive
defensive mechanism of humans.
If it never happened,
she would've denied it
without any unnecessary comments.
"I'm not a bad person."
"Who do you think I am?" Blah, blah.
Making such unnecessary comments
is derived from the instinctive
defensive mechanism of humans.
That's right.
That long story you just told us was also…
You taught us back then
when we knew nothing.
Of course, it's your fault.
No matter how much you explain,
they're just motives for the crime.
Ms. Park.
The painful story you shared with us.
In the end, that's a strong motive.
Is it not?
I've taught you well.
Yes.
-I did it.
-Mr. Kang!
Did you really rig the trial?
Seriously?
Now that we're not on the same side,
I better exercise
my right to remain silent.
See you in court, everyone.
PRO BONO
-Do you have an attorney?
-I'll be representing myself.
Those people have nothing to do with me.
They're below my standard.
-Father?
-His father-in-law?
Thank goodness you went undercover!
You taught us well.
Just know that all approvals
on Team Pro Bono
will go through me from now on.
Under someone like him,
Team Pro Bono can't do anything.
If they can't do anything,
I'll have to lay them off.
Is it weird for an attorney
to follow the firm's order?
I'll retain counsel.
I'm Oh Jung-in,
attorney for defendant Kang Da-wit.
Are a person's intentions that simple?
Is it okay for the others
to judge them so rashly?
If they interfere in matters they had
no authority over, no crime is committed.
"Not guilty."
I want to hear the truth from you.
The desire for revenge
against Yoo Baek-man.
Did that influence your trial?
Subtitle translation by: Yoon Hyewon